<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ch 3 - Hugo Publish on Hugo web framework for Fortinet Demos</title><link>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3.html</link><description>Recent content in Ch 3 - Hugo Publish on Hugo web framework for Fortinet Demos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Hugo page</title><link>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/2_task1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/2_task1.html</guid><description>Task 1 - Hugo Build When you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied with Hugo view of your content in Hugo virtual server, issue a Hugo &amp;lsquo;build&amp;rsquo; in the container CLI
hugo --minify This command &amp;ldquo;builds&amp;rdquo; your Hugo site into the container&amp;rsquo;s /public folder. We used a docker disk mount to map this folder back to your local /docs folder, so the Hugo website will automatically be copied back into your local repo You can now exit the container with ctrl + cd, or command: &amp;rsquo;exit&amp;rsquo; When you exit the container, any changes you made to the container will be lost and cannot be recovered Remember we edited the /content folder on our local OS, so those changes were not made to the container and will not be lost Further, the disk mount from local&amp;rsquo;s /docs to Container&amp;rsquo;s public AUTOMATICALLY writes the hugo build to your local OS, so those changes will not be lost If you need to continue editing, just run a new container from your built image, and run hugo&amp;rsquo;s webserver.</description></item><item><title>Task 2 - Push content to your repo</title><link>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/3_task2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/3_task2.html</guid><description>Task 2 - Push your content to GitHubo repo Finally, from your local workstation CLI, push the newly created Hugo site up to GitHub to automatically publish your Hugo Site
git add . git commit -m &amp;#34;&amp;lt;my commit message&amp;gt;&amp;#34; git push Remember we&amp;rsquo;re always working in a Git Branch, so we&amp;rsquo;ll need to issue a Pull request and merge using this procedure</description></item><item><title>- Create GitHub action for Hugo Publish</title><link>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/gittips.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/gittips.html</guid><description>GitHub Repo Getting Started (General Workflow for GitHub Repos) Once your repo and pipeline have been created, you will be provided with the GitHub repo link which you can use to clone and begin content creation. First, navigate to a desired local directory and clone the repo with the provided link: cd &amp;lt;desired parent directory&amp;gt; git clone &amp;lt;provided link&amp;gt; cd &amp;lt;cloned repo directory&amp;gt; Create a feature branch to begin working on your desired changes.</description></item><item><title>Task 3 - Create GitHub action for Hugo Publish</title><link>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/githubactions.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fortinetcloudcse.github.io/UserRepo/03chapter3/githubactions.html</guid><description>Task 3 - Create GitHub action for Hugo Publish Warning You must have proper repo permissions to setup a GitHub action. If you do not see the settings button on the top repo banner/ribbon, please reach out to the repo owner to get the proper permissions In your web browser, navigate to the GitHub repo and click on Settings in the top ribbon On the left hand nav bar, click on Pages Under Source select GitHub Actions Click Browse All Workflows Search for Hugo and then click Configure under the Hugo GitHub Actions You&amp;rsquo;ll see a hugo.</description></item></channel></rss>